<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Kunal Das]]></title><description><![CDATA[Aspiring developer | Open-Source Enthusiast | Music and Sport Aficionado]]></description><link>https://kunal1244.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 08:13:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[My 30-Day Song Challenge Answers, Combined. — Part-II]]></title><description><![CDATA[I came across an amusing challenge while browsing social media a while ago, which was to identify a song based on themes/scenarios every day for one month. Here's my take.]]></description><link>https://kunal1244.github.io/blog/posts/song-challenge-ii</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kunal1244.github.io/blog/posts/song-challenge-ii</guid><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/song-challenge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The questions.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll continue the challenge I took in the first blog post, check it out if you haven’t already. Here are the final 15 themes that I cover as part of this routine. Let me know your answers too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;16&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that is a classic favorite&lt;/strong&gt; — Has to be &lt;em&gt;Sultans of Swing&lt;/em&gt; by the Dire Straits(Sultans Of Swing / Eastbound Train) in the Pre-Rock era and &lt;em&gt;Juicy&lt;/em&gt; by Biggie Smalls(Ready to Die) in the hip-hop genre.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Knopfler’s skills on the guitar are unmatched really, or at least among the same ranks as Jimmy Page and Eric Clapton. It is a nightmare to perfectly replicate on the guitar even for professional guitarists with years of experience, although it is equally pleasant to savor those smooth transitions between bends, and the equally mesmerizing background support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s just one word to describe any Biggie track — FLOW. He was the King of East-Coast, who wrote lyrics that would come to inspire generations of rappers after him, and delivered them as smoothly as a red-hot knife on butter. There was no equal when he was at his peak.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close Misses — &lt;em&gt;Another Brick in the Wall, Part-II&lt;/em&gt; by Pink Floyd(The Wall), &lt;em&gt;Snow, Hey Oh&lt;/em&gt; by Red Hot Chili Peppers (Stadium Arcadium).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;17&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song you’d sing a duet with someone on karaoke&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;Love the Way You Lie&lt;/em&gt; by Eminem, vocals by Rihanna (Recovery).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This song is close to me, as I’d do this very frequently in school. A friend of mine killed Em’s verses, while I sufficiently backed him with Rihanna’s high-pitched vocals (My friends know I possess a great falsetto XD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;18&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song from the year you were born&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;Nas Is Like&lt;/em&gt; by Nas(single), released March 1999.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean I’ve got to have a song on this list by my favorite artist of all time (Even my ringtone is a sample from The World is Yours, the best Nas track to date in my opinion). The best lyricist of hip-hop history collaborating with DJ Premier tried to recreate the magic they put out together in the form of Illmatic in ’94, and boy were they successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;19&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that makes you think about life&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;The Yawning Grave&lt;/em&gt; by Lord Huron(Strange Trails).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That song gives me chills, yo. An eerie yet serene background and Ben Schneider’s haunting vocals make it one of the best songs I’ve heard yet. Very similar to another track by the same band, Vide Noir, from an album with the same name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;20&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that has many meanings to you&lt;/strong&gt; — Didn’t really understand the theme very well, but a song which I really admire, and which has various hues and angles to it, is &lt;em&gt;November Rain&lt;/em&gt; by Guns N’ Roses (Use Your Illusion I). Starts off really happy and takes a very dark turn indeed, with an amazing solo by Slash which has millions of covers on YouTube.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this was a philosophical theme and needed a song that conveyed different meanings to me individually, I’d pass as I’m really not much of a deep thinker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;21&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song you like with a person’s name in the title&lt;/strong&gt; — Does &lt;em&gt;Still D.R.E.&lt;/em&gt; (2001) count?
Dr. Dre is one of the most influential producer-rappers in hip-hop history, and this was his perfect return to the forefront after The Chronic’s widespread acclaim in 1992. Plus hey, there aren’t many average collaborations between him and Snoop, so yeah this was bound to be a hit. Dope-ass beat though, check it out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that moves you forward&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;Fire and the Flood&lt;/em&gt; by Vance Joy and &lt;em&gt;Hall of Fame&lt;/em&gt; by The Script, without question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I generally admire all of Vance’s songs equally, this hits different in a very positive way. Also, The Script generally write meaningful songs and having Will.I.Am from the Black Eyed Peas join them just makes it an awesome collaborative effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;23&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song you think everybody should listen to&lt;/strong&gt; — Not a song, but a phenomenon. Please listen to Linkin Park. Just do it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well I mean if you were born in the 90s you must have already listened to them. Do it again, can’t stress it enough (You can skip the album One More Light if you’re an out-and-out metal-head, but listen to it anyway I guess, it’s not half as bad as it is made out to be). Call it my personal bias, but LP is the greatest alt-rock band to ever grace the earth. Also, RIP
Chester :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song by a band you wish were still together&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;Hotel California&lt;/em&gt; by the Eagles(Album — Hotel California).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fine, I get it. Very cliché, but who cares, it’s a great song. Don Felder and Joe Walsh were the heart and soul of the group, and once Don was let out after a dragged-out fiasco, it really wasn’t the same anymore. Amazing song though, check it out if you haven’t already heard it a billion times over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;25&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song you like by an artist no longer living&lt;/strong&gt; — Woah that is not a very potent constraint. This could be a list, but I’m gonna stick to one. &lt;em&gt;Come As You Are&lt;/em&gt; by Nirvana (Nevermind). Will leave it at that. Kurt Cobain, you goddamn legend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that makes you want to fall in love&lt;/strong&gt; — Well you must have understood my love for Lord Huron by now. This has to be one of my favorite indie tracks, &lt;em&gt;When The Night Is Over&lt;/em&gt; (Vide Noir). No more explanation, listen to the song, you’ll get it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that breaks your heart&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;Make it Rain&lt;/em&gt; by Foy Vance, covered by Ed Sheeran for the TV show ‘Sons of Anarchy’.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lyrics are painful, and the music is sad, however, if I may say so, borderline sultry. Listen to Foy Vance’s version, where he sang it live at Bangor Abbey, and you’ll lose your mind. Blues Rock at its best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;28&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song by an artist whose voice you love&lt;/strong&gt; — Keira Knightley has the voice of a nightingale. Don’t believe it? Listen to her version of &lt;em&gt;Lost Stars&lt;/em&gt; from the movie Begin Again (a clichéd choice again, but it’s really that good). Enthralling to say the least. The Adam Levine version is pretty great too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song you remember from your childhood&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;Smack That&lt;/em&gt; by Akon(Konvicted).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings back memories. The first English song I had memorized all the lyrics to, and being able to sing the whole of it was an achievement like none other back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;30&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that reminds you of yourself&lt;/strong&gt; — That’s deep. &lt;em&gt;What They Do&lt;/em&gt; by the Legendary Roots Crew(Illadelph Halflife)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, you caught me, I just mentioned a banger of the top of my head, didn’t think too much into it. Though if I do have to mention similarities between the track and my personality, I’d say the precision and clarity on production, a bit of funk throughout the song, and Black Thought’s raw intelligence on the lyrics. Couldn’t find anything wrong with the song though, which is rarely the case with me.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My 30-Day Song Challenge Answers, Combined. — Part-I]]></title><description><![CDATA[I came across an amusing challenge while browsing social media a while ago, which was to identify a song based on themes/scenarios every day for one month. Here's my take.]]></description><link>https://kunal1244.github.io/blog/posts/song-challenge-i</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kunal1244.github.io/blog/posts/song-challenge-i</guid><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/song-challenge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The questions.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across an amusing challenge while browsing social media a while ago, which was to identify a song based on themes/scenarios every day for one month. Since a major chunk of the month has already passed, I thought I might as well cheat and present them all together :p.
Since this would be a really long read, I thought I’d rather break it into 2 parts of 15 songs each for better comprehensibility. I’ve also mentioned the albums in parentheses of specific tracks I’ve listed, so you can check them out as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d also like to mention that I’ve predominantly mentioned songs in English, and it is not due to any bias against the Hindi Music Industry. It’s just that most Hindi songs somehow find a way to our playlists every time, but good music in the West is something I’ve been actively trying to find out about, so this is a result of my exploits. I’ll make a separate Hindi one later maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is my list, let me know yours, and what is it exactly about a particular song that inspires you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that reminds you of summertime&lt;/strong&gt; — Donald Glover, aka Childish Gambino’s ‘&lt;em&gt;Feels Like Summer&lt;/em&gt;’ (single) also released as ‘42.26’ in his most recent album 3.15.20 (amazing btw, check it out!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, why not. Amazing production by Ludwig Göransson (who also gave us the Black Panther discography, a modern legend), a brilliant message about Global Warming, in addition to a mindblowing music video take this record as close to perfection as it could be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close Misses — &lt;em&gt;Saturday Sun&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Riptide&lt;/em&gt; by Vance Joy, &lt;em&gt;Little Talks&lt;/em&gt; by Of Monsters and Men (not a summer song per se, but I discovered it last summer so yeah, checks out)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;2&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song you like with a number in its title&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;93 ’til Infinity&lt;/em&gt; by Souls of Mischief, released as a single and a record in an album of the same name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the sickest and most underrated beats in the 90’s Alternate genre, especially when Gangsta Rap was at the top of its game, the song is a production masterclass. That this turned out to be one of the most influential albums in hip-hop history is no surprise whatsoever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close Misses — &lt;em&gt;Shook Ones, Part II&lt;/em&gt; by Mobb Deep (objectively a better song, but way too overplayed), &lt;em&gt;Bound 2&lt;/em&gt; by Kanye West (Well pre-Kardashian Kanye was the real deal)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song you like with a color in the title&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;Black Dog&lt;/em&gt; by the legendary Led Zeppelin, as part of ‘Led Zeppelin-IV’, a multi-platinum certified album (well what Zeppelin album isn’t).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonzo’s crazy but accurate rhythm coupled with Jimmy Page’s ridiculous skills on a riff created by John Paul Jones could be a great hit in itself, but Plant’s screeching yet surprisingly coherent vocals make it one of their best records ever. No wonder it was a fan favorite in all of their concerts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close Miss — &lt;em&gt;Black Skinhead&lt;/em&gt; by Kanye West(Yeezus)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that reminds you of someone you’d rather forget&lt;/strong&gt; — Well, anything by Kesha, Justin Beiber, and Demi Lovato, among many more in the massy pop genre (I mean I don’t hate all pop artists, but some were just cringe tbh). All of these remind me of my earlier teens where I would blast these every day, a part of me I’d gladly wipe out of my memory given a chance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close Miss — Prateek Kuhad. Not gonna lie, did like a few of his compositions here and there, but that dude is way overrated. I’d rather forget anyone who believes he’s the new face of Indian indie pop, there are much better acts than him out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;5&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that needs to be played loud&lt;/strong&gt; — Ah, easy-peasy. Literally any song by Siddhu Moose Wala or Bohemia, or other artists in the consumable Punjabi hip-hop genre (excluding ‘artists’ like Badshah). A major shoutout to my Northie friends for introducing me to this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that makes you want to dance&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;Can’t Stop the Feeling&lt;/em&gt; by Justin Timberlake.
The song is brimming with infectious positive energy, always tend to move my hands and legs inadvertently when listening to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close Misses — All Daler Mehndi and Pharell Williams tracks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;7&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song to drive to&lt;/strong&gt; — Depends really. If I go the generic ‘long drive through the fields’ route though, the Lumineers are great. Can’t pick a single song from their discography, all sort of sound the same really.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if we go the ‘returning home after a long day in the office’ route, I’d pick Lord Huron, Vance Joy, or Of Monsters and Men. Though they have a varied discography, I’d put on any track really, the soothing and mellow music is all I would require after a hectic day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song about drugs and alcohol&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;N.Y. State of Mind&lt;/em&gt; by Nas (Illmatic).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major chunk of 90’s gangsta rap dealt with the evergrowing crack abuse, and its negative effects on the predominantly ghetto black community. Nas perfectly summarizes the NY East Coast situation in this track, and it is a recurrent theme throughout Illmatic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close Misses — Any track from the hugely popular album Ready to Die by Notorious B.I.G.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;9&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that makes you happy&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;Here Comes The Sun&lt;/em&gt; by The Beatles (Abbey Road).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The intro lead to the song played by Paul McCartney, and the sheer innocent simplicity of its lyrics never fails to put a smile to my face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;10&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song that makes you sad&lt;/strong&gt; — Any track from Donuts, the final album by J Dilla, the GOAT producer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Listening to Donuts leaves me awestruck and sad at the same time. It’s the definition of leaving on a high, J Dilla died 3 days after releasing his final and incomparable brilliant masterpiece, of a rare infection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;11&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song you never get tired of&lt;/strong&gt; — Well this is tough, ’cause there are a lot of them. But the 2 major ones would be &lt;em&gt;Redbone&lt;/em&gt; by Childish Gambino (Awaken, My Love!), and &lt;em&gt;Blame Game&lt;/em&gt; by John Legend and Kanye (My Beautiful Dark Twisted Fantasy).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Redbone intro loop is the smoothest of them all, plus a high-pitched Troy (Community reference, watch it if you don’t get it) is all we ever wanted and needed. And though Blame Game has pretty impressive productions behind it (The whole of MBDTF does in fact), the Chris Rock outro skit is the real deal for me. Never gets old.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Close Misses — &lt;em&gt;C.R.E.A.M.&lt;/em&gt; by the Wu-Tang Clan (Enter the Wu-Tang — 36 Chambers), any track by A Tribe Called Quest, or the Legendary Roots Crew, 2 of the OG group acts of hip-hop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&quot;12&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song from your pre-teen years&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;Call Me Maybe&lt;/em&gt; by Carly Rae Jepsen
Blast this song when I’m around and watch me transform into a crazy little kid, shouting out all the lyrics, in sync.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song you like from the 70s&lt;/strong&gt; — &lt;em&gt;Time&lt;/em&gt; by Pink Floyd (The Dark Side of The Moon)
Nothing much to say here. Pure Classic. David Gilmour and his solos are the GOAT, period. If you’ve not heard of it, you are probably living under a rock. Please do me a favor and listen to the entire album in one go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song you’d love to be played at your wedding&lt;/strong&gt; — Not much scope there to be honest. A Bengali Wedding is too formal for such puny events. However, I’d be pretty psyched to have Jimmy Page’s solo in &lt;em&gt;Stairway to Heaven’s Extended 10-minute live version&lt;/em&gt; play in the background. That’d be mad.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A song you like that’s a cover by another artist&lt;/strong&gt; — Kurt Cobain’s live version of A Man Who Sold The World by David Bowie, at the 1994 MTV Awards (Unplugged Session). It’s wild to imagine that Cobain’s raspiness would so artistically compliment the song.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remaining 15 songs will be in the next blog post. Make sure you check it out!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ashish Nehra - A Legend?]]></title><description><![CDATA[Is Ashish Nehra just the sum of his performances on the field? Is it justified to remember his as an injury-ridden career of no consequence? My two cents as NehraJi announces his retirement from the game.]]></description><link>https://kunal1244.github.io/blog/posts/ashish-nehra-a-legend</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kunal1244.github.io/blog/posts/ashish-nehra-a-legend</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Durham, 26 Feb. 2003. The day belonged to a lanky left-arm seamer, who had endured a seriously sprained ankle just 2 days ago.The figures he returned were an astounding 6 for 23, that while bowling out his 10 overs straight against England. Ashish Nehra’s spell was a lesson in the art of seam bowling itself, with Alec Stewart being his only scalp not dismissed in the slip cordon. The dream performance remained his best by a mile, which says a lot about a career which ended recently, with the man being 38, an age by which almost any cricketer would have already hung up his boots. The career was, however, ravaged by injuries, which led to the end of his fledgling test career at 2005, comprising of just 17 tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But was such a rugged, seemingly inconsequential career really so irrelevant? Does an average of 42.40 in Tests reflect just the ineffectiveness of a left armer who regularly hit the 140s with the frail physicality he had?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/ashish-nehra1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ashish Nehra celebrating during his career-defining spell at Durban, 2003&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;injury-layoffs-and-comeback&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#injury-layoffs-and-comeback&quot; aria-label=&quot;injury layoffs and comeback permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Injury layoffs and comeback&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Nehraji, it was always was about putting up with his fragile structure, and his sheer denial to give up on pace that defined his career. An athlete so prone to injuries, having had 12 surgeries, Yuvraj Singh once joked, “ Ashish Nehra is the player who would get himself injured even while sleeping.” Frustrating more so were the timings of injuries, which usually occurred when Nehraji was in his rhythm, and was making real impact. Why, even his Durban spell ended with him throwing up by the side of the pitch, while he was nursing a swollen ankle. But the torrid journey has made him mentally strong, so strong that he was able to make an amazing comeback to the Indian T20 side aged 36, on the back of two hugely successful IPL seasons. He went on to become one of the top bowlers in the World T20 2016. “What works for me is my experience obviously. I know my limitations, but I always back myself. The confidence comes from the fact that I have done enough behind-the-scenes work”, he says.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nehra’s career has had its ups too, with him picking 31 wickets in 2009, following it up with 28 scalps the next year, to end up No. 2 on the world ODI wickets chart, which guaranteed him a place in the World Cup squad for 2011. He regrets turning down the offer by the then Test captain MS Dhoni and national coach Gary Kirsten to play Tests in 2009, as he felt his body could not have handled the workload of bowling 20 overs an innings. “I could have worked on my fitness harder, was just 30”, he sighs. He never complained though, “If I am doing well, I am the same guy; if I am not doing well, I am the same guy. Definitely, when you are not doing well, you do think about your game and what is going wrong, and then you think, “What can I do better?”.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/ashish-nehra2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ashish Nehra nursing an injury during a Sunrisers Hyderabad match.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-pace-issue-in-india&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-pace-issue-in-india&quot; aria-label=&quot;the pace issue in india permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The pace issue in India&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The secret lies in bowling yorkers, he believes. According to him, the failure of strong teams
such as South Africa, Australia and England to be consistent in the shortest format directly
points to the lack of quality bowlers at the death, who can deliver pacy yet accurate yorkers
at will.Why India has been lacking in the pace department, according to him is not due to
lack of talent, but sub-par management and support. Someone like Mitchell Starc is provided
with world-class facilities to preserve him, is given ample rest, which is something that Indian
pacers lack. He admires Chaminda Vaas, the Sri Lankan seamer, for being able to survive
as long as he did, in pitches tailor-made to suit Murlidharan and Dharmasena, coupled with
the hot and humid conditions, while picking a mammoth 400 ODI wickets. Umesh Yadav,
being able to bowl throughout India’s home season, that at a wonderful pace too, signifies
the growing awareness of the issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;development-of-a-lethal-pace-attack&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#development-of-a-lethal-pace-attack&quot; aria-label=&quot;development of a lethal pace attack permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Development of a lethal pace-attack&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Indian team, however, has scaled a new peak from the last 2 seasons, which experts
believe has a lot to do with the recent rise among the seamers, both in quantity and quality.
Supremely talented individuals including Jasprit Bumrah, Hardik Pandya, Jaydev Unadkat,
Barinder Sran, Mohammed Siraj have made it to the national squad, and have been performing
brilliantly at the topmost level, while the stalwarts in the likes of Mohammad Shami,
Bhuvneshwar Kumar, Umesh Yadav have established themselves among the elite playing
today across the world. The rise has been fairly synonymous with the admission of Nehra into the squad, while he himself
has been one of the top performers. Nehra had become the father-figure in the team with a
new-found pace attack of Bumrah, Pandya and Kumar. In the unforgettable match against
Bangladesh in the World T20, where India defended 2 runs off the last 3 balls, Nehra was the
one in control of the situation. A young Hardik Pandya would see the perfect fields set for his
balls while Kohli, Dhoni and Yuvraj would simply listen to his advice and act accordingly.
The T20 attack was one of the best in the world, and under Nehra’s guidance it flourished,
with Bumrah entering the top 5 in the world rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/ashish-nehra3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Nehra during the infamous match vs Bangladesh in the 2016 World T20.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;legacy&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#legacy&quot; aria-label=&quot;legacy permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Legacy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nehra’s legacy does not entirely remain behind those figures, but also in the way he has
inspired a generation to continue persevering, whatever be the odds is golden. Javagal
Srinath, the legendary pacer, in honour of Nehra’s phenomenal career said, “This is the
saddest retirement the sport has had to see since Sachin Tendulkar and will leave a hole that
cannot be filled. His expertise, way of mentoring the team, and leading from the shadows will
never be forgotten by any of the team members.” On the eve of his swansong match, Delhi &amp;#x26;
District Cricket Association renamed one of the ends of the Feroz Shah Kotla Ground as
“Ashish Nehra End” and thus Nehra becoming second bowler in the cricket history after
James Anderson (cricketer) to have bowled from the end named after him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has now made a move to commentary, which is perfect for him as his teammates regard
him as a naturally funny being. He still makes trips to his boyhood club, Sonnet, a club which
has given many greats to Indian cricket. Smart-phones are not his cup of tea, he admits, and
when asked what fans like about him, he simply answers, “Fans do not like me much.”&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Rise of Milintant Vegetarianism]]></title><description><![CDATA[The age-old vegetarian vs non-vegetarian issue may seem inconsequential, but it has managed to create a major rift within the Indian society. How did this turn into a political issue? Find out.]]></description><link>https://kunal1244.github.io/blog/posts/the-rise-of-militant-vegetarianism</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kunal1244.github.io/blog/posts/the-rise-of-militant-vegetarianism</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;India has always been plagued by symbols. People here are judged based on their
caste, creed, and the religion they belong to, hence while your appearance and
words may not always be the reflections of your beliefs and your “status” in the
society, but the symbols you carry along give you away. In case you’ve not already
figured it out, the most obvious symbol which comes to our mind when we talk
of this judgmental state is food. Though the food groups may crudely be divided
into the vegetarians, and the non-vegetarians, it is not quite that simple out here
in India, is it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/veg1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;How India eats.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-actual-lines-of-classification&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-actual-lines-of-classification&quot; aria-label=&quot;the actual lines of classification permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The actual lines of classification&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, let’s get a little catch-up on the theme. Vegetarians are basically people who consume only plant products, and alongside dairy products like milk, cheese, butter etc. The ones who also add eggs to their diet are ovo-vegetarians. If you’ve heard of the term vegans, these are the people who abstain themselves even from the dairy products. While India is looked upon by the West as a majorly vegetarian  country, the stats show otherwise. About 71% Indians consider themselves non-vegetarian, but ironically enough, the remaining vegetarians are greater than the combined might overseas! Hence it is not wrong at all to infer that India can safely be assumed to be the hub of vegetarianism, and this is exactly where a situation starts to develop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this classification seems quite sleek and simple, the application often leads to communal disruption. The thing is we Indians are really proud of our culture. “Proud &amp;#x26; vain” to be precise, though. It really is outrageous and laughable at the same time to see such puny issues be the origin of something as huge as the recent beef-ban chaos. Why, if even eggs (optional at that, in case you’re wondering!) being served to actually needy children, through a government
mandated mid-day meal scheme can be the source of disruption in a country home to the largest number of severely malnourished children; it is hard to imagine more fragile morals from these so-called “protectors” of their cultures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/veg2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Indian schoolchildren having their mid-day meal.&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-role-of-caste-hierarchy&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#the-role-of-caste-hierarchy&quot; aria-label=&quot;the role of caste hierarchy permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The role of caste hierarchy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What has rendered our society so insensitive, so inhumane that food, one of the very basic amenities of life has been sparking divisions? While the thought may be seconded by emotion and sentiment, we do need to analyze what the root causes might be. The very old and prevalent caste
hierarchy plays a major role here. The sense of purity attached with vegetarian food calls for distance, both social and physical, from its counterpart and Brahmins, were, and still are staunch advocates of the theory. And moreover, more and more communities are coming in support
of this totally baseless argument, as they desperately want themselves to be in confederation with their so-called superiors, the Brahmins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political parties draw inspiration, and these very insignificant issues start evoking a national sentiment. We need to ask ourselves why the ideas of ‘pollution’ and ‘purity’ are unquestioningly accepted and why an instinct of disgust for non-vegetarian food is blindly cultivated — even by the younger, modern, educated lot —when it only supports an insane, outdated exclusion, often along the lines of caste and religion. Many are indeed not sure why
they react that way, except for the fact that they were raised to do so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;vegetarian-hegemony&quot; style=&quot;position:relative;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#vegetarian-hegemony&quot; aria-label=&quot;vegetarian hegemony permalink&quot; class=&quot;anchor before&quot;&gt;&lt;svg aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; focusable=&quot;false&quot; height=&quot;16&quot; version=&quot;1.1&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 16 16&quot; width=&quot;16&quot;&gt;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 9h1v1H4c-1.5 0-3-1.69-3-3.5S2.55 3 4 3h4c1.45 0 3 1.69 3 3.5 0 1.41-.91 2.72-2 3.25V8.59c.58-.45 1-1.27 1-2.09C10 5.22 8.98 4 8 4H4c-.98 0-2 1.22-2 2.5S3 9 4 9zm9-3h-1v1h1c1 0 2 1.22 2 2.5S13.98 12 13 12H9c-.98 0-2-1.22-2-2.5 0-.83.42-1.64 1-2.09V6.25c-1.09.53-2 1.84-2 3.25C6 11.31 7.55 13 9 13h4c1.45 0 3-1.69 3-3.5S14.5 6 13 6z&quot;&gt;&lt;/path&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Vegetarian Hegemony&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s explore a case of vegetarian hegemony. The BJP, a political party in India built around the upper-caste Hindus obsessed with cow-protection, has been, for a few years, trying to show support to an equally non-vegetarian hating community, the Jains, by imposing a ban on the abattoirs in Mumbai for a certain period during “Paryushan Parv”, the Jain festival. This definitely was a strategic move, considering the BJP, a party which derives its funds and standing from the Gujaratis and the Marwaris, of which a significant population follows Jainism. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the Shiv Sena and the Sangh took offence, representing the Maharashtrians, who consume poultry and fish on a regular basis, which are also wary of the growing control of these communities over the market, industry etc. However, as a direct consequence of vegetarian hegemony, firstly, “Roti”, a restaurant, was made to shut down through harsh protests by the Jains, and renowned food-chains like the McDonalds, Starbucks were made to change their outlets so as to shift to a purely veg menu. The issue reached a new high, when there were reports of landlords barging into rented flats any time of the day to check whether the tenant was either cooking or storing non-vegetarian food. This has led to palpable tension over the years between resident communities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, political parties, sure, have a major hand in sparking these divisions. They will always search for the best possible situations to appeal to the sentiments of their vote banks. The recent ban for the slaughter of cattle again proved to be the catalyst, with the Kerala Youth Congress members slaughtering a cow publicly. Ironically, while most of these protestors would
turn out to be Hindus defending beef, the media, including the word of mouth will popularize and evoke the anti-Muslim sentiment. And people will be outraged, come out on streets, protest, kill a few of their own species, it is all really normal in this country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/media/veg3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Indian God Krishna placed inside a cattle shed, suggesting the reverence of cows in Indian culture&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, an appeal to all of you out there, have your views, constructively criticize and argue, but if you can’t respect the basic interests and needs of your fellow citizens, you shouldn’t even bother. Period.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Introduction]]></title><description><![CDATA[A little something about myself, and an introduction to this blog.]]></description><link>https://kunal1244.github.io/blog/posts/introduction</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kunal1244.github.io/blog/posts/introduction</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 23:46:37 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just so you do not picture someone not even remotely alike, I am not the general type you’ll often encounter on the go, or the random guy sitting next to you in a classroom. I’m more of a curious, intuitive geek who likes to think he actually has an idea of what he wants in life. However, I’m not as creepy as I may sound. I love to meet new people, know their thought processes, and make friends with the ones I find interesting. My closer friends describe me as an interesting personality, so I’d be happy to latch onto that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently started writing articles and short texts for a task I’d been given, and realized that I actually loved the work. It really helped, not just because I could give my opinion on topics which I think are important, it also gave me the motivation, the incentive to actually research and enhance my knowledge on the topic itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The topics I choose will definitely not be limited to a few genre, and rather span over various ones, sport, music, politics, education being just a few of them. I certainly do not expect everyone who gives them a read to actually take a few moments and give an honest feedback but hey, why not?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would also love to interact with you, just give me a ping at my Facebook ID, your insight would be really appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>